Guide to the Nancy Fales Garrett Papers MSS.051
Fales Library and Special Collections
Nancy Fales Garrett Papers
1965-2009
Fales Library and Special Collections
Garrett, Nancy Fales
MSS.051
5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 6 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 1 oversize folder.
2 videocassettes (vhs)
3 electronic discs (cd-rom)
Nancy Fales Garrett is a writer, director, and teacher. This collection contains original manuscripts of theater pieces, poem, short stories, a novel, published pieces, critical reviews, posters, slides, and photos related to Garrett's works.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated to the Fales Library by Nancy Fales Garrett.
Scope and Contents
The Nancy Fales Garrett Papers include original manuscripts of theater pieces, poem, short stories, a novel, published pieces, critical reviews, posters, slides, and photos related to Garrett's plays.
Arrangement
The Nancy Fales Garrett Papers are arranged into three series:
Series I: Theatre Pieces (the oversize box at the end of the collection contains oversize materials from Series I)
Series II: Poetry, Short Stories, and Reviews
Series III: Oversize Graphics
The papers are arranged in chronological order within each series.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical Note
Nancy Fales Garrett is a writer, director, and teacher. Fales Garrett began her theatrical career at LaMaMa ETC and later founded Shakespeare in the Valley, a Shakespeare workshop for teenagers. Fales Garrett's plays include Arc, Playing in Local Bands, Some Sweet Day, The Northern Kingdom, and Dora. In addition, Fales Garrett has written the screenplays The Stranger and The Northern Kingdom and been awarded playwriting fellowships from NYSCA and the National Endowment for the Arts. Fales Garrett teaches playwriting at St. Ann's School in Brooklyn, NY.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact the Fales Library with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact the Fales Library with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Off-Broadway theater; Playbills.; Librettos (documents for music); Theater -- New York (State) -- New York -- Reviews
- Series I: Theatre Pieces
  - Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "A Harvard Man": manuscript, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Babysitter": manuscript, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The Orchard": manuscript, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The Orchard": Renata Theatre program, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "The Adventures of Sadie the Goat": manuscript, [1967] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Dracula": manuscript, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "How They Made It": manuscript, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Predicates": manuscript, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Family Portrait": manuscript [see also Passion & Garbage], 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Passion & Garbage": manuscript.[see also Family Portrait], undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Surviving Death in Three Acts": manuscript [two versions], 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Surviving Death in Three Acts," photos, 1973 (Box 5)
  - "Casserole": manuscript [two versions: one with Ralph Lee], 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Casserole: an Illusion," photos, cast list, undated (Box 5)
  - "The Ark": manuscript, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "The Ark": music, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Damaging Evidence - Refracted Light", 1976 (Box 5)
  - "The Zone of Middle Dimensions": manuscript, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Nicole Willing": manuscript, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Indianhead": manuscript, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Playing in the Local Bands": manuscript, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Playing in Local Bands", 1982-1985 (Box 5)
  - Reviews, Playbills, 1983-1989 (Box 5)
  - "The Secret Life of Women": manuscript, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Travel": 2 one act plays, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "The Puppy Show": manuscript, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Some Sweet Day," playbills, photos, reviews, 1985-1990 (Box 5)
  - "Some Sweet Day": manuscript, April 4, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "Dora, Libretto": manuscript, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "Dora": music, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Dora," slides, undated (Box 6)
  - "Dora," score, libretto, photos, slides, receipts, publicity materials, playbills, reviews, 1989-2009 (Box 5)
  - "Dora: Prospect Park," video, 2001-10 (Box Shared Fales 014)
  - "Dora," photos and poster, CD-Rs, 2002-02-27 (Box Shared Fales 014)
  - "The Stranger": manuscript, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "The Stranger": videotape, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "The Northern Kingdom," script, promotional materials, undated (Box 5)
  - "The Northern Kingdom," Chris Lopez, CD-R, undated (Box Shared Fales 014)
  - "Farmville," script, 2004 (Box 5)
- Series II: Poetry, Short Stories, and Reviews
  - "Payback": novel, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Blood": fragment, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "One Decent Man": manuscript, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Down the Road": manuscript, [1992/1993] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Listening" in Hanging Loose, #62, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Meat Market" in Anima, v.1, #1, Fall 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Ragtime" in 13th Moom, v.6, #1/2, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Nes Kirby, Victoria: review of "Casserole": The Drama Review, v.18, #3, September 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Gussow, Mel: review of "Some Sweet Day": New York Times, March 23 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "One Flight Up," Susan Fales Hill manuscripts, undated (Box 7)
- Series III: Oversize Graphics
  - Graphics, Clippings, Scrapbook materials, 1965-1982 (Box 8)
  - Oversize: "The Ark": poster, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Oversize: "The Ark": musical scores, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Theater Posters, 1983, undated (Flat-file-folder 2)